{
    "QuizID": "C1",
    "QuizFrom": "2024-03-30",
    "QuizContent": [
        {
            "QuestionID": "1",
            "Question": "What is ABAP Cloud?",
            "Content": [],
            "Answers": {
                "A": "Steampunk",
                "B": "ABAP Environment",
                "C": "Development Model",
                "D": "Fantasy novel"
            },
            "RightAnswer": "C",
            "Explanation": "ABAP Cloud is the new Development Model in ABAP, to develop Clean Core and Cloud Ready Applications."
        },
        {
            "QuestionID": "2",
            "Question": "Where can you use ABAP Cloud?",
            "Content": [],
            "Answers": {
                "A": "ABAP Environment",
                "B": "S/4 HANA Public & Private Cloud",
                "C": "S/4 HANA On-Premise",
                "D": "All Environments"
            },
            "RightAnswer": "D",
            "Explanation": "ABAP Cloud is the Development Model for the future and for all Environments."
        },
        {
            "QuestionID": "3",
            "Question": "Which object is not supported in ABAP Cloud?",
            "Content": [],
            "Answers": {
                "A": "Report",
                "B": "Class",
                "C": "Function Module",
                "D": "Core Data Service"
            },
            "RightAnswer": "A",
            "Explanation": "Reports are part of the SAP GUI and are no longer supported with ABAP Cloud. Only browser front ends like Fiori are supported."
        },
        {
            "QuestionID": "4",
            "Question": "Where don't you get informations about released objects?",
            "Content": [],
            "Answers": {
                "A": "Cloudfication Repository",
                "B": "Properties View (ADT)",
                "C": "Repository Tree (ADT)",
                "D": "SE80"
            },
            "RightAnswer": "D",
            "Explanation": "The SE80 is probably still the favorite IDE for many ABAP developers, but with ABAP Cloud you primarily need the ABAP development tools to create the new artifacts."
        },
        {
            "QuestionID": "5",
            "Question": "How are jobs in ABAP Cloud scheduled in the system?",
            "Content": [],
            "Answers": {
                "A": "SM36",
                "B": "Report",
                "C": "Application Jobs",
                "D": "No need for Jobs"
            },
            "RightAnswer": "C",
            "Explanation": "Jobs are scheduled in ABAP via the Fiori App Application Jobs. But there are also APIs in ABAP and as OData for job schedulers."
        },
        {
            "QuestionID": "6",
            "Question": "What is the name of the model for structuring your own objects?",
            "Content": [],
            "Answers": {
                "A": "2-TIER Model",
                "B": "3-TIER Model",
                "C": "ABAP Cloud Model",
                "D": "There is no model"
            },
            "RightAnswer": "B",
            "Explanation": "The 3-TIER model is a central component of ABAP Cloud and provides help with structuring in-house developments in the system. The three pillars create the respective TODOs for you and SAP."
        },
        {
            "QuestionID": "7",
            "Question": "How are on-premise software components managed?",
            "Content": [],
            "Answers": {
                "A": "Report",
                "B": "Fiori App",
                "C": "ABAP Development Tools",
                "D": "SE80"
            },
            "RightAnswer": "A",
            "Explanation": "Currently, the software components can only be managed on-premise with the RSMAINTAIN_SWCOMPONENTS report (as of S/4 HANA 2022/2023)."
        },
        {
            "QuestionID": "8",
            "Question": "What do you need to access not released objects in TIER-1?",
            "Content": [],
            "Answers": {
                "A": "Access it directly",
                "B": "Build a wrapper",
                "C": "Move to TIER-3",
                "D": "Role a wrap"
            },
            "RightAnswer": "B",
            "Explanation": "If you want to use a non-released SAP object, then you have to build a wrapper on TIER-2 and release it in order to be able to use it in TIER-1."
        },
        {
            "QuestionID": "9",
            "Question": "What can't you do with software components?",
            "Content": [],
            "Answers": {
                "A": "Use it with gCTS",
                "B": "TIER-3 objects can access",
                "C": "Use released TIER-2 objects",
                "D": "Use object of other software components"
            },
            "RightAnswer": "D",
            "Explanation": "You can only use objects from other software components if they have been released. By default, use is not permitted."
        },
        {
            "QuestionID": "10",
            "Question": "How are objects released for TIER-1?",
            "Content": [],
            "Answers": {
                "A": "C1 Contract",
                "B": "Object state",
                "C": "Build on TIER-3",
                "D": "Never"
            },
            "RightAnswer": "A",
            "Explanation": "To release an object for TIER-1, you must create a C1 contract via the API State in the Properties View (ADT)."
        }
    ]
}